A Guide to the Anthony Family Papers, 1785-1952
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Anthony Family Papers, 1785-1952
Library of Virginia
35647, 35648
4.95 cu. ft.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 35647, Purchased 30 June 1997; Accession 35648, Purchased 2 October 1997.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Anthony family were prominent residents of Campbell County, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1785-1952, including letters, accounts and receipts, estate papers, and subject files of the Anthony family of Campbell County, Virginia. The letters are written primarily to Charles Anthony (1793- 1884), his daughter Callie J. Brandon (1839-1886), and his granddaughter Charles Anthony (1883-1966). Topics covered include family news, births, marriages, and deaths in the community, farming, travel, health, and the Civil War. Of particular note is a letter, dated 8 May 1862, concerning the Monitor-Merrimac battle.
The estate papers include information on the administrations of the estates of William Black, Achilles M. Douglas, John L. Douglas, William Frazier, Charles Terrell, Christopher Urquhart, and John West, Sr.
The subject files contain affidavits, bonds, commissions, and oaths, contracts and agreements, deeds, diplomas and certificates, depositions, an 1835 muster roll, obituaries, plats and surveys, poetry and lyrics, post office drafts, powers of attorney, promissory notes, genealogical information, school exercises, miscellaneous suit papers, summonses, and a copy of the will of Elizabeth Anthony, dated 1801.
Arrangement
I. Letters. II. Accounts and Receipts. III. Estate Papers. IV. Subject Files.
Contents List
- Letters
  The letters are written primarily to Charles Anthony (1793-1884), his daughter Callie J. Brandon (1839-1886), and his granddaughter Charles Anthony (1883-1966). Topics covered include family news, births, marriages, and deaths in the community, farming, travel, health, and the Civil War. Of particular note is a letter, dated 8 May 1862, concerning the Monitor-Merrimac battle.
  - Annie Anthony, 1905-1911 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Benjamin Haden Anthony, 1852-1881 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bernard Anthony, 1895-1896 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Charles Anthony
    - 1812-1819 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1820-1829 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1830-1839 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1840-1844 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1845-1847 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1848-1849 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1850-1859 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1860-1869 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1870-1875 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Charlie Anthony
    - 1908-1919 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1927 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 1930-1931 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1934 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1935-1940 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Ella Anthony, 1880-1881 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Homer L. Anthony, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Jennie M. Brandon Anthony, 1858, 1874 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - John W. Anthony, 1812, 1821, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - John W. Anthony, 1848 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - John William Anthony
    - 1860-1899 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - 1900-1915, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Mrs. J.W. Anthony, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Mark Anthony, 1847-1859 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Martha Anthony, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Martha Davis Anthony, 1895-1911 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Martha Davis Haden Anthony, 1854, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Mary B. Anthony, 1907 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Morgiana Anthony, 1849-1883, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Reid Anthony, 1910-1911 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Sallie Lizzie Arnold, 1860 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Sue Atkins, 1860-1880, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Callie Anthony Brandon
    - 1847 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1855-1857 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1858-1859 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1860 (January-June) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 1860 (July-December) (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 1861 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 1862 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 1863-1864 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 1867-1869 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 1870-1871 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 1872-1873 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 1874-1876 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 1880-1885 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Undated (Box 3, Folder 14-16)
  - Victor Morgiana Brandon, 1880-1882, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Benjamin Haden, 1811 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - W.B. Haden, 1861-1862 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Mahetta (Hettie) Lumsden, 1866-1877 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - F.C. Peters, 1868-1874 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - J.S. Peters, 1888, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Sue A. Peters, 1867-1869 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - F.E. Samples, 1868-1871 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Accounts and Receipts
  - 1789-1791, 1841 (Account Book) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1798-1829 (Box 4, Folder 4-23)
  - 1830-1844 (Box 5, Folder 1-15)
  - 1845-1856 (Box 6, Folder 1-13)
  - 1857-1876 (Box 7, Folder 1-20)
  - 1877-1914 (Box 8, Folder 1-4)
  - Undated (Box 8, Folder 5-9)
  - Pieces (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Tax Receipts, 1785-1899, undated (Box 8, Folder 11-15)
- Estate Papers
  The estate papers include information on the administrations of the estates of William Black, Achilles M. Douglas, John L. Douglas, William Frazier, Charles Terrell, Christopher Urquhart, and John West, Sr.
  - William Black, 1830-1867 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
  - Achilles M. Douglas, 1794-1837 (Box 9, Folder 4-5)
  - John L. Douglas, 1815-1850, undated (Box 9, Folder 6-13)
  - William Frazier, 1790-1859, undated (Box 10, Folder 1-5)
  - Charles Terrell, 1810-1850 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Christopher Urquhart, 1835-1868 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - John West, Sr., 1819-1849, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Misc. Administrator's Accounts, Appraisments, Inventories, and Sales (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Estate Papers (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Account of Sale of Property of Orison V. Layne to Satisfy Debt, 1837-1843 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Subject Files
  The subject files contain affidavits, bonds, commissions, and oaths, contracts and agreements, deeds, diplomas and certificates, depositions, an 1835 muster roll, obituaries, plats and surveys, poetry and lyrics, post office drafts, powers of attorney, promissory notes, genealogical information, school exercises, miscellaneous suit papers, summonses, and a copy of the will of Elizabeth Anthony, dated 1801.
  - Affadavits, 1823-1848 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Bonds, Commissions, Oaths, 1794-1853 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Contracts and Agreements, 1810-1869 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Deeds, 1818-1844 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Depositions, 1825-1838 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Diplomas and Certificates (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Memorandum Book, 1811-1817 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Muster Roll, 1835 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Obituaries (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Petition for Relief from Military Duty, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Photographs (Box 11, Folder 11a)
  - Plats and Surveys (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Poetry and Lyrics (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Post Office Drafts (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Powers of Attorney, 1817, 1839 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Promissory Notes, 1822-1842 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Reference File/Genealogical Information (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - School Exercises (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Suit Papers, 1820-1838 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Summonses, 1833-1864 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Warrant, 1831 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Will of Elizabeth Anthony, 1801 (copy) (Box 11, Folder 22)